高清电影网 http://M1080.com 提供字幕下载
把它们想象成这样就行
Just picture them as this.
作为地球上仅存安置点人类
As sons and daughters of possibly the sole remaining
的子女
human settlement on earth.
你们是人类存亡的关键
You're a critical part of what stands between us and extinction.
因此  你们有义务安全返回
Therefore, you have an obligation to return to us safely.
只要牢记训练内容
And if you remember your training,
你们就能做到
you will.
祝你们好运  一路平安  天佑美国
Good luck, godspeed, and God bless America.
美利坚!  美利坚!
USA! USA!
出发吧
Let's go!
[墙上的字:欢迎来到死亡之区!  保持警惕!]
Welcome to the Dead Zone! Look alive out there!
不错嘛!
Sweet!
Berg  你到底过不过来帮忙啊?
Hey Berg, are you gonna help us out or what?
不过去  我快打到第五级了
No, I don't. I'm almost at level five.
你们听到了吗?
Did you hear that?
我听到了
I did.
我们应该离开这儿
We should bail.
这怎么行  我们不能跑  我们有任务
Oh, hey, we can't just bail. We have orders.
你知道整个城市一个月
Do you have any idea how much medicine
要消耗多少药品吗?
this city goes through a month?
人们需要药物存活  我们不能跑...
We need pharmaceutics to survive. We can't just bail or...
天哪  你怎么和我爸口气一样
God, you sound just like my dad.
谢谢
Thank you.
我可不是在夸你
Yeah, it was not a compliment.
伙计们  来点百忧解吧  说不定能让你们兴奋点
Oh here, guys. Take some Prozac. It might cheer you up.
我说了我听到了声响
I told you, I heard something.
Perry  我们撤吧
Perry, let's bail.
Perry!
我们有任务在身  Julie
We have orders, Julie.
反正也不会是什么
It was nothing anyway.
你肯定是在大惊小怪
You're being paranoid, okay?
Perry!
瞄准他们头部!
Aim for the head!
好漂亮的手表!
Nice watch!
我并不以此为豪
Now I'm not proud of this.
而且我希望这会儿
In fact, I'd appreciate it
你能略过这段  看看别处
if you might look away for a moment here.
我并不喜欢伤害人类
I do not like hurting people.
但没办法  现在世道就是这样
But this is the world now.
渴求活肉的新饿潮让大家欲罢不能
The new hunger is a very powerful thing.
如果我不把他全部吃掉  留下他的大脑
If I don't eat all of him, if I spare his brain,
他会重新站起来  成为我这样的行尸走肉
He will rise up and become a corpse like me.
不过  如果我吃了他
But if I do ...
我就会有他的记忆  他的思想
I get his memories, his thoughts.
他的感受
His feelings.
我很抱歉  可是我忍不住
I'm sorry, I just can't help it.
大脑是精华部分
The brain is the best part,
它让我有重新为人的感觉
the part that makes me feel human again.
喜欢这烟花吗  Perry?
You like it, Perry ?
我不想伤害你
I do not wanna hurt you.
我只是想感受你的感受
I just wanna feel what you felt.
- 谢谢  - 我可不是在夸你
- Thank you. - Yeah, it was not a compliment.
我说了我听到了声响
I told you I heard something.
Perry!
瞄准他们头部
Aim for the head!
你说了只是几天而已
You said a few days.
已经过去很多天了
It's been a few days.
我必须回家
I have to go home.
要...待在一起
S... stay together.
外面不安全
It isn't safe.
搞什么!
What!
这是Julie
It's Julie.
活人
Living.
吃了她
Eat.
吃掉
Eat!
噢  我的天啊
Oh, my God.
我们走
We go.
吃掉
Eat.
这边
This way.
跟我走
Come with me.
什么?
What?
不
No.
只是想...帮忙
Want to ... help.
谁叫你帮了?
Who the hell ask you?
我...
I...
...喜欢她
...like her.
没事的
It's okay.
才怪嘞
Sure it is.
- 去那边  停车场  - 马上到
- Over there, the garage. - Hold on.
噢  现在看到你真高兴
Oh, I'm so happy to see you right now.
你没事吧?
You okay?
呃...R?
Oh...R?
你...开车
You...drive.
好主意
Good idea.
天啊  好冷啊
Jesus... I'm freezing.
我得靠边停一下
I'll have to pull over.
这应该是我爸指挥撤离的最后一个街区了
This would be the last neighborhood my dad evacuated.
我们得找个房子然后吃点东西
We need to get to a house and have some food.
噢  天啊
Oh, God.
好了  来
Okay, come on.
噢  锁着的
Oh man, it is locked.
噢  酷
Oh, cool.
看他们有这个诶
Look what they have.
宝丽莱拍立得
Obsolete polaroid.
茄子!
Cheese!
没事的  看?
It's all right, see?
是吧
Yeah.
记录回忆是很重要的  知道不?
It is important to preserve memories, you know?
尤其是世界即将灭亡的当下
Especially now with the world is on its way out.
眼前的一切  都可能是最后一次看到
Everything you see, you may be seeing for the last time.
Perry以前常这么说
Perry used to say that.
给  照张相吧
Here. Take a picture.
我累极了
I'm exhausted.
楼上的床铺还不坏  我去睡觉了
The bed upstairs isn't too rum , so I'm gonna go to sleep.
晚安
Good night.
R
听着  R  我在想...
Look, R, I was thinking ...
其实你可以...
You know, you could ...
也睡在那如果你想的话
Sleep in there if you want.
睡地板上
On the floor.
这房子挺吓人的  所以...
This house has creeped me out, so ...
好吧
Okay.
我脸色太苍白了  应该多出去走走
I'm so pale. I should get out more.
我应该吃好点  现在这样子真差劲
I should eat better. My posture is terrible.
应该站直一点
I should stand up straighter.
我要是昂首挺胸  别人也会更尊重我
People would respect me more if I stood up straighter.
我到底是怎么了?  我只想和人交流而已
What's wrong with me? I just want to connect.
但为什么不行呢?
Why can't I connect with people?
哦  想起来了
Oh, right.
因为我已经死了
It's because I'm dead.
其实没必要为难自己
I shouldn't be so hard on myself.
毕竟大家都是死人
I mean, we're all dead.
这女孩是死人  那家伙是死人
This girl is dead. That guy is dead.
角落里那哥们肯定也是死人
That guy in the corner is definitely dead.
天啊  这群人看起来糟透了
Jesus, these guys look awful.
真希望能做个自我介绍
I wish I could introduce myself,
可惜我忘了自己名字
but I don't remember my name anymore.
我猜它是个"R"开头的词
I mean, I think it's started with an "R",
但也仅此而已了
but that's all I have left.
我记不起自己的名字  父母或是生前的工作
I can not remember my name or my parents or my job.
尽管从这身装扮来看  我生前可能没工作
Although my hoodie would suggest I was unemployed.
有时我会看着其他同伴  想象他们生前是什么身份
Sometimes I look at the others and try to imagine what they were.
你大概是清洁工
You were a janitor.
你可能是某集团总裁家的贵公子
You were the rich son of a corporate CEO.
你也许是...
You were ...
私人健身教练
A personal trainer.
但现在只是具僵尸
Now you're a corpse.
有段时间  我很想搞清楚
I found a hard time piecing together
这种末日之灾发生的原因
how this whole apocalypse thing happened.
可能是生化战争  或是空气传染病
Could have been chemical warfare, or airborne virus,..
亦或是放射性物质大爆发产生的畸形生物
or a radioactive outbreak monkey.
但都不重要了  我们成了僵尸  接受现实吧
But it doesn't really matter. This is what we are now.
这是我作为僵尸的普通一天
This is a typical day for me.
我趿着步子  偶尔会撞到人
I shuffled around, occasionally bumping into people.
但我无法向被撞到的人道歉  或是说点什么
Unable to apologize, or say much of anything.
生前时光肯定比现在好得多
It must have been so much better before.
那时候大家都可以尽情说话
When everyone could express themselves,
能够畅快交谈
communicate their feelings
喜欢有人陪伴
And just enjoy each other's company.
我的许多同类
A lot of us had made our
都在这个机场里安家  我不明白个中缘由
home here at this airport. I don't know why.
可能是在等着什么吧
People waited at the airport, I guess.
但僵尸又能在这里等什么呢
But I'm not sure what we are all waiting for.
哦天哪  大家叫这伙人"皮包骨"
Oh man. They call these guys "Boneys".
他们一般不骚扰我们
They don't bother us much.
以一切有心跳的活物为食
But they'd eat anything with a heartbeat.
虽然我也是
I mean, I will too,
但至少我有些抵触
but at least I'm conflicted about it.
可能哪天  我们也会变成"皮包骨"
We'll all become them someday.
如果放任不管就会变成那样吧
At some point you just give up, I guess.
先是失去了希望  之后一步步  再也不能回头
You lose all hope. After that, there is no turning back.
天哪真恶心  停下停下  别刨了  只会更丑
Oh, man. Gross. Stop, stop, dont pick it. You're making it worse.
这就是我以后要过的日子
This is what I have to look forward to.
真扫兴
It's kind of a bummer.
我不想这么过
I don't want to be this way.
我很孤独  找不到方向
I'm lonely, I'm lost.
现在是真找不着方向了
I mean, I'm literally lost.
之前没来过机场的这片区域
I've never been in this part of the airport before.
这也是俩迷途的小孩
These guys are lost too.
四处乱晃但永远到不了什么地方
Wandering around but never getting anywhere.
他们是不是感觉不自由?
Did they feel trapped?
是不是想过更好的生活?
Did they want more than this?
难道只有我这么想吗?
Am I the only one?
这是我的死党
This is my best friend.
所谓死党  我俩也就偶尔对着哼哼
By best friend I mean we occasionally grunted..
或笨拙地盯着对方而已
and stared awkwardly at each other.
间或可以称得上是在交谈
We even have almost a conversation sometimes.
每天都这样
Days passed this way.
但有时  我们能说出完整的词
But sometimes, we even find the actual words ...
比如  "好饿"
Words like: Hungry.
- 或者  - "城市"
- And... - City.
虽然我们无法交流
Even though we can't communicate,
但我们对食物的喜好相同
we do share similar taste in food.
结伴出去觅食是正确的选择
Travelling in pack is kinda make sense.
尤其是当外面的人类  不论老幼
Especially when everyone and their grandmother's
都想打爆你的头时
trying to shoot you in the head all the time.
天啊  我们走的真慢
God, we move slow.
估计得花不少时间
This could take a while.
大家好  感谢你们今天的辛苦工作
Hello, and thank you for your service today.
媒体报道  自从这一瘟疫摧毁了我们的世界
In media, ever since this plague destoyed our world,
你觉得有可能找到治愈的方子吗
Do you think we're getting the stuff for the cure?
"这个世界的存亡..."
And the survival of our world ...
没人会相信有解药了  Julie
No one believes in a cure anymore, Julie.
"依靠你们这样的志愿者
For volunteers like you,
从隔离墙外搜集资源"
to gather resources from beyond the wall.
但首先  提醒一句
But first a word of caution.
僵尸看起来像人类  但是它们不是
Corpses look human, they are not.
它们不会思考  不会流血
They do not think, they do not bleed.
即使它们曾是你的母亲
Whether they were your mother
或你最好的朋友  你现在已不可能挽救它们了
or your best friend, they are beyond your help.
它们无情无义
They are uncaring, unfeeling..
不知悔改
incapable of remorse.
听起来还真像我认识的某人啊  老爸
Sounds like someone I know, Dad.
让我好受一些
To feel a little better.
让我有一些生气
A little less dead.
Perry  我想我爱你
Perry, I think I love you.
说话呀
Say something.
别什么都不说
Don't you say nothing...
不  我...
No, I'm...
我也爱你  Julie
I think I love you too, Julie.
我很怀念飞机
I miss airplanes.
我妈妈曾经说  飞机在天上看着像是蚀刻素描
My mom used to say that it looked like an Etch a Sketch up there.
是啊
Yeah.
我很高兴你记着那些事
I like that you remember that kind of stuff.
如果你不记着  它们就会...
If you don't, it's just...
随风而逝了
All be gone, you know.
是啊  这个世界一片混乱
Yeah, the world is so messed up.
也不全是
Not all of it.
芝士球
Cheese ball!
Perry.
Perry!
Perry  你在哪儿? 回答我!
Perry, where are you? Answer me!
Ju... lie...
安全...
Safe...
过来...
Come...
我不知道自己在做什么
I don't know what I'm doing.
我是怎么了?
What's wrong with me?
这些家伙绝不会带活人回家的
These other guys will never bring a living person home.
你知道为什么吗? 疯子才做这种傻事
You know why? Because that's crazy.
现在  他们以为她是我们的一员
Right now, they think she's just another one of us.
新的家庭成员
A new addition to the family.
如果他们能思考
They would think I was insane.
会认为我疯了
If they could think.
为什么一切如此诡异?
Why life has to be so weird?
我到底在做什么?
What am I doing?
到家了
Home.
不...
Not...
吃...
Eaten...
让你...
Keep...
...安全
...you safe.
好吧
All right,
或许我能想得更清楚点
maybe I could have thought this through a little more.
我看得出女孩这时候需要独处
I can tell when a girl needs her space.
要想了解一个人有很多种方式
There's a lot of ways to get to know a person.
吃掉她死去男友的大脑
Eating her dead boyfriend's brain
是一种最极端的方式  不过...
is one of the more unorthodox methods, but...
今天是个特殊的日子
This is a special occasion.
特殊的日子?
A special occasion, Sir?
今天是我妈妈的生日
It's my mom's birthday.
- 为Diane  - 为妈妈
- To Diane. - To mom.
是的
Yep.
Perry  Julie说你做农业方面的工作?
So Perry, Julie tells me you've been working in agriculture?
但你没想过
But tell me you would
要和你爸爸去做建筑方面的工作吧
never consider going to work construction with your father?
隔离墙那里我们很缺人手
You know, on The Wall we need good people.
别理他  Perry
Don't mind him, Perr.
我爸爸拯救人类的方案是
Dad's idea in saving humanity...
建一个巨大的混凝土箱子
is to build a really big concrete box,
让大家都待在里面
put everyone in it,
然后举着枪守护在门口  直到我们老去  死去
and then wait at the door with guns until we grow old and die.
Julie  没有隔离墙  我们现在就是在吃人脑了
Well, Julie, without the wall we would be eating...
而不是吃饭
brains now instead of rice.
爸爸
Dad.
这是穿过隔离墙的唯一通道
This is the only way to pass The Wall,
否则我们就过不去了
Otherwise we just stopped.
- 走吗?  -好的
- Okay?  - Okay.
来吧
Come on.
没关系  来呀
It's not that bad, come on.
我两天没听到我爸的消息了  Julie
I haven't heard from him for two days, Julie.
他正忙隔离墙的施工  Perry  他在工作
He's on construction detail, Perry. He's working.
我爸能几周不跟我联系
My Dad goes weeks without checking in.
好了  轻点走
Okay, come quietly.
嘿
Hey.
没事的
It's gonna be okay.
嗯
Yeah.
爸爸
Dad.
Perr...
快点  我们走
Come on, let's go.
难怪她那么怕我
No wonder she's so afraid of me.
我得换个方式了
I need a different approach.
好  我来了
Okay, here we go.
别吓人  别吓人  别吓人
Don't be creepy, don't be creepy, don't be creepy.
你要做什么?
What are you doing?
请让我一个人待着
Please leave me alone.
为什么?
Why me?
你为什么救我?
Why did you save me?
别...
Don't...
哭
...cry.
保护
Safe ...
保护你
Keep you safe.
你是什么?
What are you?
我饿了
I am hungry.
放我走
Just let me go.
不...不安全
N-N-Not safe.
不安全?
Not safe?
啊  不安全
Ah, it's not safe.
那你得去给我弄点吃的
Well then you're just gonna have to go and get me some food.
因为我快饿死了
Because I'm starving.
求你了...
Please ...
有点吃的我会很感激你的
I would be very grateful for some food.
好的
Okay
天啊!
God!
糟了!
Shit!
别...
Don't...
跑...
Run...
来  安全
Come. Safe.
谢谢
Thank you.
装死人
Be dead.
会吗?
Okay?
太夸张了
It's too much.
我告诉过你
I told you ...
不...安全
Not...safe.
是的  我明白了
Yeah, I get that.
但我真的很饿
I really am hungry though.
太棒了
Yes!
唔天哪
Hmm, my God.
哦! 不!
Oh, no!
别盯着人家! 你又举止怪异了
Stop staring! You're acting weird again.
谢谢
Thank you.
啊  哎...
Oh, man ...
我都不记得上一次喝啤酒是什么时候了
Can't remember the last time I had a beer.
你也坏不到哪儿去嘛  僵尸先生
You can't be all that bad, Mister Zombie.
我的...
My...
名字...
Name...
你也有名字吗?
You have a name?
你叫什么?
What is your name?
Rrr...
R什么?
Rrr?
现阶段进展很不顺利
This stage is not going well.
我恨不得再死一遍
I want to die all over again.
你名字的首字母是R吗?
Did your name start with R?
是Robert吗?
Robert?
还是Richard?
Richard?
Randy?  呃...
Randy? Uh ...
是不是Raphael?  或者Ricardo?
Raphael? Ricardo?
要不我就叫你R好了
Why don't I just call you R?
好歹也算个开始  是不是
I mean, that's a start, right?
R  我想回家了
I want to go home, R.
外面不安全
Not safe.
这个我明白
I get that.
而且  听着
And look ...
我知道你救了我的命  我也对此很感激
I know that you saved my life and I'm grateful for that.
但是是你带我走进这个地方的
But you walked me into this place.
所以我知道你也能再带着我走出去
So I know that you can walk me out again.
哦不  她不能走  她才刚刚来到这里呢
Oh, no! She can't leave, she's just got here.
快告诉她必须得等  快告诉她  其他僵尸会注意到的
Tell her she has to wait, tell her ... they'll notice.
你必须...
You have...
得等着
to wait.
他们...会...
They... will...
注意到你的
Notice...
哼  说的还不错嘛
Heh, not bad.
等多久
How long?
就...几天
Few... days.
他们会...逐渐忘了你的存在
They'll.. forget.
然后...你就会没事了
You'll... be okay.
还有其他像你一样的僵尸么
Are there others like you?
我是说...
I mean...
我从来都没听说过僵尸还会说话的
I've never ever heard a corpse talking before.
我指的是...  除了呻吟之外
I mean, apart from, you know... groaning.
好吧
Okay.
就几天  是吧?
Few days, huh?
那这几天困在这个鬼地方  我又能做些什么呢
And what am I supposed to do in a few days around here anyway.
这真是太棒了
This is awesome!
你也想来试试吗?
Do you wanna try?
我的天...
Oh, God...
有点耐心
Oh, wait for it.
打住  打住...  选一只脚踩油门
Okay, okay... pick a foot.
你这是两只脚一起开车  只能选一只
You're using two feet, pick... Pick one foot.
这还差不多
There you go.
对喽
There you go!
好的  现在两只手都放在方向盘上
Allright, two hands on the wheel.
我的天  R
Jesus, R!
你把这么漂亮的车撞坏了
This was a beautiful car!
这么多唱片是怎么回事?
What's with all the vinyl?
你没学会怎么用iPod吗?
Couldn't figure out how to work an iPod?
(唱片)听起来...效果更好
Better...sound.
哈  你还是个纯粹主义者  是不?
Ah, you're a purist, eh?
(听唱片)让我觉得...
More...
更有活力...
Alive...
嗯  那倒是
Yeah, that's true.
但是麻烦多多
Lot more trouble though.
你看看  你刚刚又耸肩了
There you go again, shrugging.
别老耸肩  你个耸肩癖
Stop shrugging, shrugger!
你总是做这样模棱两可的动作
It's really not a committal gesture.
又来?
Really?
你这些唱片都很酷
These are really cool records.
你上哪儿找的这么多?
How did you get all these?
我...喜欢收集东西
I... collect things.
是的  这我看得出来
Yeah, I can see that.
我的朋友  你真是个可怕的存在
You, my friend, are a horror.
我知道一家超棒的唱片店
I know this awesome record store.
你一定会很喜欢  那家店可酷了
You'll love it, that's so cool.
是被毁之前很酷
Was so cool.
好嘞
All right then.
现在好多了
Much better.
R  我可以问你一件事吗?
R, can I ask you something?
我男朋友...
My boyfriend...
他死在那里了
He died back there,
他还会回来吗?
Will he come back
会变成你这样的僵尸回来么?
as one of you?
也许这样就很好了
That's good, I guess.
他经历过一些事
Something happened to him.
他经历过了很多事
A lot of things happened to him.
但可能熬到一定程度  他终究是
But I guess there just came a point where
扛不住了吧
he couldn't aborb anymore.
只不过  在我的世界里
It's just ... in my world,
总有人离开我死去
people die all the time.
所以  并不是
So, you know, it's not like
他死了我一点都不难过
I'm not sad that he's gone.
我其实很伤心
Because I am.
但我也许一直都在
But I think I have been...
为这一天到来做准备
preparing for it,
而且准备很久很久了
for a really long time.
你到底是什么?
What are you?
哇  睡觉一定很舒服吧
Man, it must be nice to sleep.
我希望我能睡着
I wish I could.
我希望我能做梦
I wish I could dream.
这只是奢望  我没得选择
That's not really an option for me.
死人没法做梦
The dead don't dream.
这是我们做的最贴近做梦的事情了
This is as closest as we get.
你确定吗  孩子?
You sure about this, son?
那么  欢迎你的加入
Welcome then.
对于你痛失至亲  我很难过
Sorry for your loss.
我也是
Me too.
给他也拿一把  然后教他怎么使用
Get him one and show him how to use it.
Berg  你到底来不来这儿帮忙啊?
Hey Berg, are you gonna help us out or what?
我快到第五级了
I'm almost at level five.
你们听到了吗
Did you hear that?
我听到了 我们应该离开这儿
I did. We should bail.
我们不能跑  我们有任务
We can not just bail. We have orders.
你怎么和我爸口气一样
You sound just like my dad.
你...
D'you...
感觉到了么?
Feel it?
你是不是...
Do you...
感觉到了...
feel it ...
是不?
Yeah?
我嘞个去  是我爸
Holy shit, it's my dad.
退后!
Get back!
他会杀了你的
He would have killed you.
如果他看到你  他肯定会一枪打在你头上
If he'd saw you, he would have shot you in the head.
然后你就永远的去了
And you're just begone.
这些衣服还是湿的
These clothes are soaking still,
我得把它们铺开晾干
I'm gonna lay them out to dry.
别紧张!
Oh, relax!
我勒个去!
Holy shit!
别看
Don't look.
好吧
Okay.
我勒个去!
Holy shit!
嘿
Hey.
你是不是必须要吃人啊?
Do you have to eat people?
是的
Yeah.
要不然你就会死?
Or you'll die?
- 是  - 但是你并没有吃了我
- Yup - But you didn't eat me.
你救了我
You rescued me,
很多次
Like... a bunch.
被困在里面肯定很难过吧
It must be hard being stuck in there.
我看到你在努力
And I can see you trying,
人类就是这样的
That's what people do.
我们总是努力变得更好
You know, we try to be better.
有时候我会觉得有些厌倦
Sometimes I get sick of it a little bit.
但是看看你...
But look at you...
你努力多了
You try so much harder than
比任何我所知的人类都努力
any human you might have seen.
你是个好人  R
You're a good person, R.
无论如何
Anyway.
是我干的
It was me.
什么是你干的?
What was you?
我想说
I mean...
- 自己其实隐约知道了吧  - 你知道?
- I guess I kind of knew that.  - You did?
嗯
Yeah.
我倒是希望不是你干的
I guess I hope that you didn't.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
Julie...
我真的很...  抱歉
I'm so... sorry.
死人是不睡觉的
The dead do not sleep.
假设这世上的工作任你们挑
If you guys can have any job in the world,
而且一切都和现在不同
and pretend that everything is totally different.
你们会想做什么?
What would you want to do?
- 看护  - 是么?
- Nursing. - Yeah?
嗯
Yeah.
治病
Healing people,
救人
Saving lives.
还有就是找到...  找到治愈良药
Yeah, and finding... finding a cure.
这个我喜欢
I like that.
我觉得总有一天  会有人
I think someday someone's
找出解决的方法  然后...
gonna figure out this whole thing, and...
在全世界到处发掘
Exhume the world.
发掘?
Exhume?
那是什么意思?
And... and what does that mean?
- 发掘以后复活  - 意思是挖掘
- Exhume means to like revive. - It means to dig up
把僵尸挖出来复活
as in digging up a corpse.
随你怎么理解
Whatever!
你在这干什么呢?
What the hell are you doing here?
哇  你现在是真的在做梦么?
Woah, are you actually dreaming right now?
- 我不确定  - 僵尸  你是不能做梦的
- I'm not sure. - You can't dream, corpse.
- 人类才能做梦  - 冷静点  Perry
- Dreaming is for humans. - Chill out, Perry.
他要是想就可以做梦
He can dream if he wants to.
你呢  R?
What about you, R?
你有想做的事情么?
What do you wanna be?
我不知道
I don't know.
我都不知道我是谁
I don't even know who I am.
只要你想  就可以成为任何人
You can be whatever you want.
大家不都这么说的么?
Isn't that what they say?
我们都可以  对吧?  你和我一起吗?
We can, right? You and me?
绝不可能  小白脸
It's not gonna happen, loverboy.
在你告诉她你吃了她前男友后就不可能了
Not after you told her you ate her ex.
耸一下肩
Shrug.
别做梦了  你不能想当什么就当什么
So much for dreaming. You can't be whatever you want.
一直以来我都是行动缓慢  脸色苍白
All I ever be is a slow, pale,
弯腰驼背  目光死寂的僵尸而已
Hunched-over, dead-eyed zombie.
我在妄想什么
What I think is going to happen
指望她会留下来和我在一起吗?
that she'd actually want to stay with me?
没用的
It's helpless.
奢求太多就只能是如此下场
This is what I get for wanting more.
我应该满足现状
I should just be happy with what I had.
接受境况一成不变的现实
Things don't change, I need to accept that.
麻木不仁反而更容易度日
It's easier not to feel.
然后我就不会像现在这样难过了
And I would not have to feel like this.
- 报上名来  - 是我  Kevin
- Identify yourself!  - It's just me, Kevin.
- 没事了  我很好  - 别动
- It's okay, I'm fine.  - Just stop right there!
没事的
It's okay.
- 我没被感染  - 我说别动  Julie
- I'm not infected.  - I said stop, Julie.
好吧  好吧
Okay, fine, fine.
她还好吗?
Is she okay?
没问题  长官
Clear, Sir.
爸爸
Hi, dad.
我派了六组人去找你
I sent half a dozen units out looking for you.
- Nora说你被带进...  - 是的
- Nora said you were taken into...  - Yes, I was.
我逃了出来  沿途躲进房子躲在郊外  然后...
I escaped, I was holed up in houses, suburbs and...
找到辆车  回来了
I found a car, so I came here.
Julie  你确定没被咬?
Julie, are you sure nothing bit you?
- 爸  你看我像被感染了吗?  - 我们得确保安全
- Do I look infected to you, Dad? - We have to be safe.
是的  我明白
Yeah, I know, I know.
我发誓我没事
I'm fine, though, I promise.
我以为失去你了
I thought I lost you.
你没失去我  爸爸
Well you didn't, Dad.
我回来了
I'm here.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
是啊  回来真好
Yeah, good to be back.
我要回家  调整一下
So I'm just going to go home. I'm gonna blend in.
别想那么多
I'm gonna stop thinking so much.
我要忘了她
I'm gonna forget about her.
像我忘掉其他事一样把她忘了
Just like I forget about everything else.
我要...
I'm gonna...
见鬼  好冷
Oh, shit, I'm cold.
这就是寒冷的感觉么?
Is that what this is?
- 僵尸明明感受不到冷  - 喂
- Corpses don't get cold.  - Yo.
我们...  来这里
We... coming here.
皮包骨们把我赶了出来
Boneys, they chased me out,
到处找你
came to find you.
她在哪里?
Where is she?
回家了
Went home.
- 你还好吧?  - 不好
- Are you okay?  - No.
婊子无情  老弟
Bitches, man.
皮包骨们...  正在...  找你
Boneys... are looking... for you.
还有她...
And her...
她触发了...  什么...
She started... something...
我看见了...
I saw...
图像...
pictures...
就在昨晚...
last night...
回忆起...
Memories...
我妈妈...
My mom...
夏天...
Summer time...
奶油...
Cream...
小麦...
Wheat...
一个女孩...
A girl...
- 是梦  - 梦?
- Dream!  - A dream?
我们...  正有所转变
We are... changing things.
- 没错  - 是的
- We are.  - We are.
我得告诉她
I have to tell her.
你们帮我吗?
Will you help?
帮我
Help.
找她?
Exhume?
他们说...
They said...
这他妈没问题
fuck yeah.
在这儿等
Wait here.
小心
Be careful.
好的
Okay.
那...  我会在这儿等
So... I'll wait here.
没关系  来呀
It's not that bad, come on.
Julie和我给大家带来了希望
Julie and I were giving the others hope.
并且迅速蔓延开来
And it was spreading fast.
我猜皮包骨不愿乐见其成
I guess the Boneys didn't like that,
所以才要找我们
that must be why they are looking for us.
我得告诉Julie
I have to tell Julie,
我得和她解释发生了什么  免得为时已晚
I have to explain what is happening before it is too late.
我必须这么做  哦  不
I have to. Oh, no. Oh, no.
去  找你的朋友去  嘘!  快走
Please, go. Go with your friends. Shoo!
离我远点  就这样  很好
Leave me. That's it, okay.
不  我是说真的  Nora
No, I'm serious, Nora!
僵尸不过是我们随便想的蠢名字
I mean, corpse's just a stupid name that we came up with
去称呼那些我们不能理解的事物
for a state of being we do not understand.
好吧
Yeah.
天啊
My God!
我这是怎么了?
What is wrong with me?
好吧  我...
Okay, I...
我得跟你说件事儿
I gotta tell you something.
很诡异  别被吓到
This is kinda weird, please do not freak out.
不会的
No.
但是...
But...
我真的很想他
I actually miss him.
你...  你想他?
You... you miss him?
- 我对他没兴趣...  - 类似于...
- I'm not interested in him...  - Like ...
你喜欢他
Like you're attracted to him.
就像他能当你男朋友的那种喜欢
Like he could be your boyfriend.
当你的呆瓜小僵尸男友?
Your zombie zombie boyfriend?
我知道现在很难遇见新的男生
I know it's really hard to meet guys right now with
我很肯定  因为世界末日什么的
the apocalypse and stuff, trust me.
我知道你想念Perry...
And I know you miss Perry...
好吗?  但Julie  这太诡异了
Okay? But Julie, this is weird.
就像...
Like...
我还希望网络能用
I wish the internet would still working,
可以上网查查你到底怎么回事
so I could just look up whatever it is that's wrong with you.
闭嘴
Shut up.
好吧
All right.
好的
Okay.
我要睡了
I'm getting ready for bed.
嘿...
Hey...
很高兴你回来了
I'm glad you're back.
嗯
Yeah.
做个关于你那僵尸的美梦
Have sweet dreams about your zombie.
好吧
All right.
Julie.
R
你来这儿干什么?
What are you doing here?
我来见你
I came to see you.
R
你不能就这样跑过来
You can't just do that.
很危险
It's dangerous.
Griggio  闭嘴  我要睡觉
Griggio, shut up, I'm trying to sleep.
对不起
Sorry.
上帝呀  R
Jesus, R!
你疯了吗?
Are you crazy?
这儿的人不像我
The people here, they are not like me.
如果看见你会杀了你  你知道吗?
If they see you, you will get killed. You understand that?
我知道
Yes.
- 你在自言自语吗?  - 没有
- Are you talking to yourself?  - No!
说真的  到底怎么了  Julie?
Seriously, what is going on here, Julie?
噢  天啊
Oh, my God!
就是他么?
Is that him?
是啊
Yeaah.
你好呀
(What)'s up?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我知道  我也很抱歉
I know. I'm sorry too.
其实我很想你
I actually missed you.
我也是
Me too.
有意思  你比我记忆中要温暖
It's funny, you're warmer than I remember.
是巡逻队
It's the patrol.
快点  进来
Come on, get inside.
来啊
Come on.
你很走运  我爸爸被叫去处理紧急事件了
You're lucky my Dad got pulled into some emergency thing.
今晚你在这里很安全  R
You're safe here tonight, R.
可过了今晚  我就不知道该怎么办了
After that, I do not know what we're gonna do.
你是怎么死的?
How did you die?
我不...  记得了
I don't... remember.
你多大了?
How old are you?
因为你可能二十几岁
Because you could be 20-something.
也可能十几岁
But you could also be a teenager,
脸长的嫩  像十几岁的孩子
you know, you have one of those faces.
哦  我的天哪
Oh, my God!
我竟然闻不到你的气味
I can't even smell you,
你身上没有腐味  他身上没腐臭味
you do not smell rotten. He does not smell rotten.
太不可思议了
It's amazing!
Nora  他不是来接受采访的  打住吧
Nora, he didn't come here for an interview. Stop.
你为什么到这儿来  R?
Why did you come here, R?
要展示给...  所有人看
To show... everyone.
展示什么?
Show them what?
我们是可以转化的
That we can change.
R  这儿没人会相信的
R, no one here is ever gonna buy that.
连把你送他们面前解释的机会都没有
Not that we can get you even close enough to tell them.
他们一见到你  马上就会轰烂你的脑袋
As soon as they saw you, they would blow your head to beds.
等一下...
Wait a minute...
你刚才说了"我们"?
Did you say "We"?
我们当中的很多...  都在转化...
Lots of us... changing...
睡着的时候做梦
Dreaming.
那可真是非同小可
That's kind of a big deal.
我们得赶紧...  行动
We have to move... fast.
- 什么意思?  - 皮包骨...
- What do you mean? - Boneys...
在到处抓我...
Chasing me...
他们在抓我们
They're chasing us.
好了  咱们得去找我爸爸
Okay, we have to go to my Dad.
这主意太烂了
That is a very bad idea.
不  Nora  他以前很通情达理
No, Nora, he was a reasonable guy once.
不不  我觉得你是糊涂了
No, no, I think you're confused.
以前你妈妈才通情达理
It was your mom that was the reasonable one.
而你爸爸呢  足足把你禁足了一年...
That was your Dad, that grounded you for a year...
就因为你偷喝了水蜜桃利口酒
for stealing Peach Schnapps.
你爸大概会这么说  "给我打爆这些僵尸的脑袋"
Assume it's your dad eliciting, "Shoot corpses in the head!"
难道还能有别的办法么  Nora?
What other choice do we have, Nora?
无论如何  我们得把他弄出这城市
Still, we have to get him through the city.
留这儿肯定会被人发现的
Someone will definitely see you.
没有太多时间了
Not much time.
咱们可以帮他伪装
We can fix him up.
什么?
What?
我留了些化妆品  想着特殊场合能用上
I have some make-up that I was saving for some special occasion
现在显然不太可能了
that obviously isn't gonna happen.
对啊  咱们可以试试
Yeah, we could.
咱们可以先上个粉底...
We can put on a little bit of foundation...
也许再刷点腮红
Maybe a little blush.
很可能需要很多腮红
Probably a lot of blush.
没门
No way.
可以有
Yeah way.
请你换首歌好么?
Would you change this song, please?
怎么了  很带劲啊
Why? It's funny!
我可不这么想
I think it's not.
等等
Hold up.
你可真帅
You look hot!
怎么了?
What?
没什么
Nothing.
不过...  你看上去真不错
It's just... you look nice.
我不知道我爸会怎么做
I don't know how my dad's gonna be.
这方法有点超乎寻常  可能根本行不通
Yeah, it's kind of crazy. This might not work.
是啊
Yeah.
不管如何  咱们在一起
No matter what, we stay together.
我们正改变着一切
We're changing everything.
我知道
I know.
在一起...  答应我好么?
Stay together... promise?
我答应你
I promise.
- 嘿  到上场的时候了  - 好了  咱们去吧
- Hey, it's game time.  - Allright, let's do this.
抱歉
Excuse me.
- 你们几个去哪?  - 去见我爸爸  Kevin
- Where are you guys headed? - To see my Dad, Kevin.
Grigio小姐  我不能让你们进去
Miss Grigio, I can't let you guys in.
现在这附近都高级警戒
We are in high alert around here.
为什么?
Why?
- 发生什么事了?  - 这是机密
- What is going on?  - It's classified.
好啦  我们也有机密事务要汇报  通融一下吧
All right, well, we have our own classified business, so come on!
嘿
Hey.
说几句人话  说几句人话
Say something human, say something human.
你好么?
How are you?
- 妥了  - 他很好
- Nailed it!  - He's fine.
好了  你俩在这儿等着
Okay, you guys wait here.
你来这儿干什么?
What are you doing here?
怎么了?  这都是干什么呢?
What is going on? What is all this?
不确定  反正不太妙
Not sure, but it's not good.
我们得到报告
We've been gathering reports,
为数可观的大批骷髅和僵尸
there are sizable packs of skeletons and corpses
正向我们逼近
coming toward us.
还不知道原因  但要是他们来袭...
We do not know why, but if they're here to attack...
我们就束手无策了  敌众我寡
Nothing we can do about it, too many of them, too few of us...
所以我希望你回家  锁好门
So I want you to get home, lock down the house.
我在你房间放了一把枪
I had a gun there at your room.
是这把么?
This?
行  好了
Yeah, okay.
- 我得和你谈谈  - Julie...
- I need to talk to you. - Julie...
爸爸  这很重要
Dad, it's important.
这听上去很荒谬  但是
This is gonna sound pretty crazy, but,
我认为那些僵尸在复活
I think the dead are coming back to life.
确实一派胡言
That does sound crazy.
他们正在转变  爸爸
They are changing, Dad.
我也没法解释  总归是自我治愈
I don't know. They're somehow curing themselves.
你觉得他们在自愈?  怎么个自愈法?
Do you think they are curing themselves? How is that?
我看见了
I saw it.
这事真的在发生
It's really happening!
Julie  你知道什么正在发生么
You know what is happening, Julie?
正在发生的是
What's happening is
他们的数量与日俱增  而我们人数日益减少
everyday there're more of them and less of us.
他们不会自愈
They are not curing themselves!
他们只会吃我们  不会转变为吃素的
We are their food source. They are not becoming vegan.
他们不吃西兰花  只吃人脑
They do not eat broccoli, they eat brains!
你妈还有你男友都没能幸免
Your mother's and your boyfriend's included.
懂了么?  所以你给我清醒点
Okay? So I want you to wake up!
我来解释
I'll explain.
行么?
Okay?
你向我解释  我来帮你转达
Explain yourself to me so I can speak your word.
我能搞定
I got this.
赶紧回家去
Get yourself home,
找个隐蔽之处藏起来
barricade yourself in the shelter.
这儿已经够乱的了  你得...
There's enough stuff there that you can...
嗨
Hi.
你是谁?
Who are you?
他是R
This is R.
没问你  我在问他
I didn't ask you, I asked him.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我是...
I am...
你是僵尸?
You're a corpse?
他救过我的命
He saved my life.
他保护了我
He took care of me.
我触动了他的什么地方  然后...
I triggered something in him and...
引发了他们所有人的变化
that must have sparked something in all of them.
现在是他让我一触即发了
Now he's triggered something in me!
爸爸  不要  爸爸
Dad, no! Dad!
我们只想帮忙
We wanna help.
求你了  他们想帮忙  不会攻击我们
Please, they don't wanna attack us. They wanna help.
我们正逐渐好起来
We're getting better.
形势不可能越来越好  只可能每况愈下
Things don't get better, things get worse.
谁要是被咬到  谁就会被感染
People get bit, then they get infected,
- 然后被我一枪爆头  - 不  爸爸
- Then I shoot them in the head.  - No, Dad.
这事曾在你妈妈身上应验
That's what happened to your mother,
现在也会由他印证
and that's what gonna happen to him.
真是非常抱歉  Griggio先生
I'm really sorry, Mr. Griggio.
快走  离开这里  无论如何都要平安  好吗
Go... get out of here and be safe, no matter what, okay?
- Julie...  - 我得走了
- Julie...  - I have to go.
你不会对我开枪的
You ain't gonna shoot me.
不  不  我会的  绝对会
Yes. Yeah, I will. Totally.
好吧
Okay.
事情本可以进展更好的
That could have gone better.
我得去警告我的朋友们
I need to warn my friends.
- 去哪儿  - 体育场
- Where? - The stadium.
靠
Shit.
快去地铁
Go to the subway.
哇
Wow!
抱歉借过一下
Please excuse me.
借过  抱歉
Excuse me. Sorry.
欢迎  来了  终于来了
Please welcome, come. Coming through.
嗨
Hi.
Julie?
我们准备好...
We're ready for...
- 去打仗了  - 是啊  看得出来
- a fight.  - Yeah, I can see that.
人类士兵正在赶来
The soldiers are coming,
皮包骨兵步步紧逼
Boneys are closing in.
他们已经来了
They're here now.
- 挡住他们  - 我们会的
- Keep them out.  - We will.
快跑
Run.
- 大家散开  右侧一队  左侧一队  - 是的长官
- Spread here, right side and to your left.  - Aye, sir.
- 不许射伤女孩  - 我们不会的
- Do not shoot the girl! - We will not.
这边  跟上
This way, come on.
长官  您女儿确实跟僵尸在一起
Sir, your daughter is with the corpses,
我找到了其他僵尸
I've got others.
这里安全
It's okay.
待命
Standby.
谢谢
Thank you.
见鬼了  我们该打哪边?
Who the hell that we shoot?
打这个混球
This asshole.
嗨
Hi.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
嗨
Hi.
我们发现僵尸正在打骷髅  长官
We see corpses fighting skeletons, Sir.
收到  我们这边也看到了
Copy that, we are seeing that over here too.
抱歉  你能重复一遍吗?
Sorry, can you repeat that?
收到  我们发现僵尸正在打骷髅  长官
Roger that. We're seeing corpses fighting skeletons, Sir.
靠
Shit!
这下完了
It's over.
我会保护你的安全
I'll keep you safe.
你没事吧?
You're okay?
R
R?  求求你  求求你
R? Please, please!
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
没事
Yes.
哇
Wow!
R
下一枪就会瞄准脑袋了
Next one's the head.
- 离他远点  Julie  - 不
- Move away from him, Julie. - No!
- Julie  马上让开  - 爸
- Julie, move now!  - Dad.
你必须要听我说
You have to listen to me.
我知道我们失去了所有人
I know we lost everybody.
我知道你失去了妈妈
I know you lost mom.
但是你我  大家都好好站在这儿
But you and me, we're still here.
我们可以改变这一切
We can fix all this.
我们可以重新开始
We can start over.
他们需要我们的帮助
They need our help.
求求你了  爸爸  看看他
Please, Dad, look at him.
他是不同的
He is different.
他...
He is...
天啊.
God.
流血了
Bleeding.
他流血了  爸爸
He is bleeding, Dad.
僵尸不会流血的!
Corpses don't bleed!
哦  天啊!
Oh, God!
你活过来了
You are alive!
他活过来了
He's alive!
R  你活过来了
R, you are alive.
伤口疼吗?
Does it hurt?
疼吗?  是啊
Yes? Yeah!
长官
Sir.
我是Griggio将军
This is General Grigio.
情况有变
Situation has changed.
赶紧带上他一起走
Let's get him sit the hell out of here.
你还在流血吗?
Are you still bleeding?
是的
Yes.
很好
Good.
抱歉
Sorry.
一方面说来  胸口中枪真的很疼
On the one hand, getting shot in the chest hurt,
相当疼
like a lot.
另一方面  能流血
But on the other, it feel good to bleed,
能感到疼痛  感受爱  真是太好了
to feel pain, to feel love.
我希望自己可以说  我们也用爱治愈了皮包骨
I wish I could say we cured the boneys with love.
但实际上  我们只能一锅端了他们
But really, we just straight up kill them all.
这些家伙已经没救了  也没人觉得灭了他们有什么不好
These guys kinda messed up and no one felt bad about it.
他们已经变不回来了
They were too far about to change.
说实在的  这次我们和人类合作得很不错
It's actually a really good bonding experience for us and the humans.
两方一旦合起伙来  皮包骨就没有了胜算
Once we joined forces, they didn't stand a chance.
那些没被杀掉的也渐渐枯竭至死
The ones we didn't kill just wasted away.
而我们其他人
And the rest of us,
重新学习怎么生活
Well, we kinda learned how to live again.
有一阵子  我们中的很多人似乎忘却了生活
For a while, it seemed like a lot of us forgot what that meant.
人类开始接纳我们  与我们沟通
The humans began to accept us, connect with us.
教我们生活
Teach us.
这就是治愈的关键
This was the key to the cure.
一开始这有些吓人  但是...
It was scary at first, but...
所有伟大的事物开始时都是有些吓人的
Every great thing starts out a little scary,
不是吗?
doesn't it?
一切就这么开始了
This is how it happened.
世界就是这样... 恢复如初的
This is how the world was... exhumed.
要帮忙吗?
Need some help?
嗯
Yeah.
我有...  僵尸的硬指头
I have... zombie fingers.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 给你  - 哦  没事儿的
- Here.  - Oh, it's okay.
- 我不介意被雨淋湿  - 我坚持这样
- I do not mind the rain.  - Oh, I insist.
我叫...
I am...
叫Marc...  Marcus
Marc...  Marcus.
我叫Emily
Emily.
你非常...  好看
You are... very pretty.
谢谢  Marcus
Thank you, Marcus.
现在你应该说...
Now you're supposed to say...
我也很好看
I am pretty too.
R
什么?
Yeah?
你想起你的名字了吗?
Do you remember your name yet?
没有
No.
你知道吗  你其实可以给自己起一个
Well you know, you could just give yourself one.
选一个  哪个都行
Pick one, whatever you want.
- 我喜欢叫R  - 真的吗?
- I like R.  - Really?
你不想知道你以前叫什么吗?
You don't want to know what it was?
不想找回以前的生活吗?
You don't want your old life back?
不想
No.
我喜欢现在这样
I want this one.
只是R就足够了?
Just R, eh?
就R了
Just R.
我每天都在做什么啊?
What am I doing with my life?